alliantcreditunion.com 2015-06-24

# Alliant Credit Union | Privacy Policy

Alliant, your member-owned financial institution, is committed to providing a safe place to save and borrow money at very competitive rates. Alliant is equally committed to protecting members' privacy and you can be confident that financial privacy is a priority of Alliant. Alliant gives all members this Privacy Notice to explain how Alliant collects, uses and safeguards its members' personal financial information.

**Member Information Collected.** Alliant collects nonpublic personal member information from the following sources:

  * Membership and loan applications and other member initiated applications and forms;
  * Member account transactions with Alliant or other financial institutions; and
  * Consumer and credit reporting agencies.

Member Information Disclosed. Alliant may disclose all of the information collected, as described above, to companies that perform marketing services on behalf of Alliant or to other financial institutions with whom Alliant has joint marketing agreements. At no time does Alliant sell or share information with companies not included in providing services directly or assisting us in providing services to our members. To protect our members' privacy, Alliant only conducts business with organizations that agree to maintain strong confidentiality protections and limits the use of information Alliant provides. Alliant may also disclose nonpublic personal information about its members under other circumstances as permitted or required by law. These disclosures typically include:

  * Information to maintain or service a member's account;
  * Conduct the operations of Alliant;
  * Follow member instructions as authorized; or
  * Protect the security of Alliant financial records.

If a member decides to terminate his/her membership or become an inactive member, Alliant will adhere to the privacy policies and practices as described in this notice.

**How Alliant Protects Its Members' Information.**  
Alliant restricts access to nonpublic personal information about its members to Alliant employees who have a specific business purpose in utilizing member data. Alliant employees are trained in the importance of confidentiality and member privacy by maintaining physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with federal regulations and leading industry practices to safeguard members' nonpublic personal information. 

**What Members Can Do To Help Protect Their Privacy**.  
While Alliant is committed to protecting the privacy of its members, you can help safeguard personal information by following these simple guidelines: 

  * Upon receipt of your VISA¨ Debit Card and/or Convenience Card, verify the information on the front and sign the back panel immediately.
  * Report a lost or stolen card(s) immediately to Alliant at 800-328-1935. After business hours, please call 866-861-5411.
  * Protect your card(s) at all times by carrying only the ones you intend to use. Store all other cards in a safe place.
  * Be aware of your surroundings when approaching an ATM. Make sure no one can oversee you enter your PIN by shielding the keypad with your hand or body.
  * Memorize your PIN and keep it confidential. Do not write it on the card or keep it in your wallet.
  * Make sure the merchant returns your card and check it to make sure it's your card.
  * Keep your ATM transaction and check card receipts. Log them into your check register. Destroy the carbons if present.
  * Never give your card information over the phone unless you initiate the call.
  * Never pre-sign your checks.
  * Balance your checkbook each month and report any unauthorized transactions immediately.
  * Treat all of your financial information as confidential and proprietary.

**Use of Online Technologies to Collect Information**

Alliant may use technologies to store information on your computer when you visit an Alliant Credit Union website. For example, cookies may be used within Alliant Credit Union websites to enhance website security, improve website effectiveness, tailor the sites to your individual preferences, and improve our marketing campaigns.

Cookies are a string of data sent between a server and a web browser to help track how you are using our websites and improve your online experience. Cookies are not used to retrieve any data from your hard drive, nor can they run a program on your computer. Alliant uses cookies to help protect your accounts from unauthorized users and to maintain session integrity and enable enhanced security. Cookies are also used to help us understand your interests and needs and to provide you with a customized online experience.

A pixel tag, also known as a web bug in an embedded image, is an invisible tag placed on a webpage to register when a particular computer visits that specific page. These tags and beacons are used in combination with cookies. Alliant places these on its web properties and in online advertisements to better personalize your experience with Alliant and to understand website usage and patterns.

**Accepting Cookies.** Most web browsers automatically accept cookies. If you do not wish to receive cookies, refer to your browser's online help for further instructions and information on setting cookie preferences. If you turn off cookies, you may not be able to use some Alliant Online Banking features. 

**Third-Party Websites.** The Alliant web properties may direct you to other sites on the Internet to provide additional information or services that may be of interest to you. Third-party websites may have privacy and security policies different from Alliant Credit Union. Please review the privacy and security policies of websites reached through links from Alliant Credit Union websites.

If you have any questions concerning this policy, please visit a Service Center or contact the 24/7Member Contact Center at 800-328-1935.

Privacy Notice
